

Mani Meskartehrani

Gmail ((778) 361- 0725 Vancouver,BC,CA in LinkedIn



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-orientated, proactive and responsible engineer, with a get-it-done, on-time and high-quality product spirit. I am an SEO specialist and an aspiring front-end developer. I have 6+ years of experience in the IT industry. Currently, I focus on learning React. Js and TypeScript. I typically use React. js and JavaScript to create components and user interfaces. In the end, I can help companies to develop more SEO-friendly websites.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS

- Working experience with the most well-known Frontend library such as
- Experienced with programming languages such as HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Familiar with website architecture and UX/UI best practices.
- Conducted responsive design and technical SEO.

Key Skills

- HTML5 / CSS3 / SASS
- JavaScript
- PHP / CMS
- React.js
- Github/Git

- Node.js
- On-page SEO
- **Technical SEO**
- Responsive Design
- **REST API**

WORK HISTORY

Website Specialist (SEO)

IPM-IRNIC | Tehran, Iran

Jun 2016 - Jan 2020

- Conduct website optimization to increase reachability by resolving technical issues HTML/ CSS and JavaScript.
- Improved website API by changing XML code to better performance in connectivity and accessibility.
- Developed new features to enhance user experience using React.js and SASS.
- Participated in weakly frontend knowledge sharing sessions and sharing some new information with my colleagues.

Frontend Web Developer | Volunteer

Oct 2012 - Jan 2014

Kaj Real Estate | Tehran, Iran

- Designed and developed Front-end of the store's website using HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript technology.
- Maintained website by refactoring and fixing reported bugs.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration | Digital Marketing

Oct 2020 – Jan 2022

University of Canada West – BC, CA

Bachelor of Engineering | Software University of Guilan - Rasht, Iran

Sep 2007 – July 2012